HANNA TEFERA

San Diego, CA, 92124

Phone: 619-632-2485 | Email: hanna1tefera@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/hanna-tefera

Github: https://github.com/HannaBella | Portfolio: https://hannabella.github.io/Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Economics and lifelong dedication to learning. Accomplished AS Degree in IT and recently, have earned a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from UCSD Extension Coding Bootcamp. The program greatly enhanced my skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, ReactJs and NodeJs. Enthusiastic about developing websites and apps with a focus on responsive design and development. Effective both in collaborative and individual work and known as problem-solver and detail oriented. Experienced in working under fast paced and stressful work environment and awarded as excellent passenger service handling agent of the year(2013).

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, NodeJs, Handlebars, MySQL, MongoDB, Sequelize, Mongoose, Express & Poort IS

Express & ReactJS.

Applications/Tools: Git, Github, Visual Studio, Heroku and Slack
PROJECTS

Cinephile Central | Repo: github.com/HannaBella/Cinephile-Central.gits | Deployed: hannabella.github.io/Cinephile-Central/

- It is an app that serves as a one-stop shop for all movie fans. With one search users can discover movie reviews from top critics and free streaming.
- Designed and built the front end for a search, result and detail page for movie review feature. Consumed New YorkTimes api, used JQuery, to retrieve search results and render the UI. In addition, OMDB api used to fetch imdb id that was used to retrieve streaming site.
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, JSON

chefMEup | Github Repo: https://github.com/matteuc/chef-me-up.git | **Deployed:** https://chef-me-up.herokuapp.com

- chefMEup is an interactive app that renders possible recipes based on the users ingredients in their fridge. Signed in user can save their favorite recipes and even can share their own recipe.
- Responsible for database design, association and query. Built ingredient and recipe api.
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, handlebars, MySQL, Sequelize, NodeJs, Express, and Heroku

Mheels | Github Repo: https://github.com/rgonz166/project3.git | Deployed: https://mheels.herokuapp.com

- Mheels is an app that tracks food truck and locate vendors near to users. The app not only shows the vendor location but users can view menu of their chosen food truck.
- Build most of the components and the general layout including the client side API.
- ReactJS, CSS, Reactstrap, JavaScript, Auth0, MongoDB, Mongoose, NodeJs, Google API, Express, Axios and Heroku

EXPERIENCE

Passenger Service Agent Washington Dulles Airport , Dulles, VA

 Lufthansa
 2011 – 2014

 Ethiopian Airlines
 2012 – 2015

- Acknowledge customers presence and greet customers in a professional manner.
- Prepare daily routine plan and assign about 15 agents for their duty.
- Verify document and visa requirement, check-in passengers, and issue board pass for more than 200 passengers.
- Reschedule misconnected passengers which demand quick problem solving skills and efficiency under fast paced and stressful work environment.

Statistician Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Central Statistics Agency 2008 - 2010

• Analyze data and prepare monthly and quarterly report for 25 to 30 internal users.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development: UCSD Extension, San Diego, CA 2019

AS Degree in Information Technology: Northern Virginia Community College, Sterling, VA

Graduated with Summa cum laude (GPA 3.93/4) 2014 - 2016

BA in Economics: Alemaya University, Alemaya 2003 - 2006

Awards

Dean's List: Spring 2014, Fall 2014, Spring 2015,